Yasir Gaji

Lagos, Nigeria



yasirgaji@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/yasirgaji



+234 813 977 7929



https://yasirgaji.dev

Summary

I Facilitate continuous improvement across all levels of an organization.

I am a collaborative Product Manager with expertise building mature agile teams that deliver quality, on-deadline products that drive corporate objectives with interactive features which drive business growth and improve user experience.

And a creative Web Engineer with a few years of experience leveraging Mark-up, Javascript, and CMS technologies to build responsive websites, web applications, and software.

Experience



Product Manager

Intech NG

Aug 2021 - Present (6 months +)

Currently managing the cloud hosting service and crafting methods on how to get the product known to the world

PCI. Founder

PLEASANT CODES INC.

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month +) Great Software is built by Great Teams

At PCI we help businesses succeed through our reliable, fast, smart, efficient, and excellent services.

We're also on a mission to ensure Nigerians are not "illiterates of the 21st century" by helping them learn, unlearn, relearn and equipping them with the present market required skills through the Project-Encoode.

PRODUCT MANAGER

FAZSION

Jul 2020 - Aug 2021 (1 year 2 months)

Drove all-inclusive improvements to efficiency and accuracy by spearheading enterprise-wide Ecommerce Business Life Cycle (EBLC).

Worked with the product team to re-create and craft a scalable and robust application to help users make bulk orders at a blazing fast speed and the best user experience.

Increased Customer Base By 60% during the year 2020 due to implementation of responsive designs to improve UX.

Key Responsibilities:

- 1. Developing and overseeing growth strategies of the Fazsion B2B Platform.
- 2. Developing new business leads through digital marketing and Improving User Experience.
- 3. Proper management of products on the b2b platform
- 4. Merchandising sales or increasing Fazsion brand presence.

TheYutes Web Engineer

TheYutes

Jun 2019 - Nov 2020 (1 year 6 months)

Worked closely with the UI/UX team to translate design mock-ups into an elegant, fast, responsive website.

Developed the entire E-commerce Business website with the CMS technology, Maintained active conversation with the team to ensure the app met its needs, Researched to aid development by 80%

Played a key role in merging designs and application code to the finished skinned and functioning product.

bafska Web Engineer

Bafsta Nigeria

Aug 2020 - Sep 2020 (2 months)

Revamped the entire E-commerce Business website with the CMS technology, Maintained active conversation with the team to ensure the website met its needs.

- Created High-quality web designs.
- Integrated Payment Gateway setup.
- Developed high quality designs.

Web Engineer

FAZSION

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 (6 months)

Helped build, develop, test, and debug responsive designs that would stand out not just only by the interface, but by the psychology, experience, and professional coding indentation for the Content Managing System.

As the Front-end Developer working closely with the UI/UX team to translate design mock-ups into elegant, fast, responsive websites and web applications.

Principal duties and responsibilities are as follows - but not limited to:

- 1. Develop new user-facing features
- 2. Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- 3. Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- 4. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability

- 5. Assure that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end
- 6. Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders
- 7. Maintain technical knowledge of web front-end industry standards, best practices and trends and evangelising these within the company.

Web Engineer

The Mindset Africa

Sep 2019 - Nov 2019 (3 months)

Contract project As the CMS Developer working closely with the UI/UX team to translate design mockups into elegant, fast, responsive websites. Principal duties and responsibilities are as follows - but not limited to.

- 1. Develop new user-facing features
- 2. Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- 3. Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs

Co Facilitator

wificombat

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019 (4 months)

Served as Technical Team Lead on educating and bridging the gap in tech adoption to accelerate the main technologies driving the 4th industrial revolution.

Offered summer enrichment programs where students gain a sense of empowerment, independence and self-confidence as they learn to articulate their creativity in new ways by using Front-End technologies.

Education



Lagos State University

Bachelor's degree (In View), Physics 2019 - 2023



Javascript Aug 2016 - Sep 2019

DOLPHIN SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL

2015 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

Design Theory - Udemy UC-BS5Q1PSB

Javascript Masterclass - Udemy

Product Management - Udemy

UC-ecc35a1b-44bd-477e-827a-c02318446137

Skills

JavaScript • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Product Management • Responsive Web Design • Project Management • E-commerce • Wireframing • React.js • Node.js • Solidity

Honors & Awards



Recognition of outstanding entrepreneurial excellence - National Union Of Lagos

Division Students, Lagos State University

Sep 2021

In Recognition of outstanding entrepreneurial excellence